[Music]
something beside
me a light to the
kerosene and the places aren't real
anymore and the faces don't say
anything in the silent
light of the Mind wind blown
sphere it's a
game Devil's
[Music]
chest Devil's chest
clown welcome to Devil's chess club I'm
Aaron good today my guest is former CIA
officer and CIA torture whistleblower
John kyaku we're going to be discussing
a number of subjects including Trump's
strange Gaza removal plan um the JFK
disclosure that Trump seems to be
looking to achieve and also 9/11 and uh
in the context of Syria being now run by
alqaeda and the final solution in uh
Palestine uh being attempted by
Netanyahu and apparently Trump so please
check the show notes for a link to
John's substack page and to his other
Ventures as
well Devil's chess club is part of the
American exception podcast if you want
to see this episode in its entirety and
if you appreciate this kind of research
and analysis on the Deep politics of the
US Empire consider subscribing to the
American exception podcast on patreon WE
current have an ongoing series on Max
arvo's groundbreaking article on Jack
Ruby as well as our long running gray
Alliance series which looks at the
Lansky Teamster Syndicate CIA Massad
threads running through the JFK
assassination Watergate and Beyond the
URL is patreon.com American exception
either way please kindly like this video
And subscribe to this American exception
Channel
John kyaku great to be back with you um
happy to speak with you thanks for the
invitation so there there is so much
going on and uh a a lot of it falls into
the category of bad but also seeming to
accelerate the end of us and gmany or
seeming to accelerate the nuclear
doomsday that might be coming because
it's so crazy and it seems the US Empire
is in such a bad way at the moment so
the the most explosive Ive and recent
thing is Trump's decision announcement
that it's time to ethnically cleanse
Gaza and uh as someone who was spent
time in the Central Intelligence Agency
and you specialized in the Middle East
and you know were a an expert on this
area what's what's your take on Trump
and this genocidal ethnic cleansing plan
I mean ethnic cleansing is technically
not considered genocide by parts of
international law but I I actually think
that the reason for that distinction is
because of Israel in the west and the US
that they've that they have now that I
look at it I'm like oh God that's why
you have this weird like ethnic
cleansing genocide separation and I bet
it's because the US and the West has
always had this this EXA this exact case
in mind and they wanted to be able to
say that ethnic cleansing is somehow not
genocide but what do you make of trump
doing this and reversing US policy the
two-state solution even if it was a fake
plan anyway they haven't fully rebuked
it like this before so what's the
significance of this WOW there is so
much to say about this Aaron first of
all you're exactly right this is a this
is a proposed genocide it is a war crime
under international law to forcibly
remove a people and seize their land
it's Crystal Clear in international law
you cannot do this uh it's a violation
and I would note too not only has this
already been roundly
condemned by every government in the
region but the Saudis issued a statement
of condemnation at 440 a.m. that's how
strongly they felt about it even Jordan
and Egypt that really have to tow the US
line most of the time came out and said
this is a terrible idea and it's never
going to work and frankly the only
people who support or would support this
kind of of illegal genocide uh are the
most extreme
rightwing of the Israeli government you
know it was amazing to me to see the the
video of Donald Trump making this absurd
proposal while sitting next to Benjamin
Netanyahu as Netanyahu smiled and nodded
his head so listen this is not going to
happen it's never going to happen and if
if Trump did anything with this stupid
announcement it is that he doomed the
Abraham Accords which in my view were a
terrible idea in the first
place right and I mean some people have
made jokes that Trump is like an
accelerationist you know that he is
attempting to ramp up the belligerence
and illegitimacy of the of the of the US
Empire so that it will implode and
collapse faster I
mean and they're they're usually joking
when when they say this of course but it
it does seem like this is the case I
mean I'm trying to game out what happens
if they attempt this they I don't think
that they would as as much as Egypt and
Jordan are total puppets of the US I
feel like they do have domestic
realities that they must contend with
and that they would potentially be at
risk for being ousted by their own oh
yeah population absolutely and both both
countries have have seen uprisings uh in
in my lifetime and look at it this way
too fully 50% of the population of
Jordan is Palestinian right right these
are these are refugees and the children
and grandchildren of refugees and they
have to the the Jordanian government has
to be sensitive to the to the wants of
its Palestinian population you know
another thing
too about a week ago a member of the
Trump Administration floated the idea of
taking all
Palestinians and forcibly moving them to
an island in Indonesia that too is a war
crime you can't do that but nobody
really paid any attention a week ago I I
talked about it a couple of times but
nobody paid any attention well now the
president of the United States is
floating the idea and it's just so
absurd and so patently illegal and so
comprehensively
popular that it just will never happen
if anything it it weakens Donald
Trump right but he I mean this is the
strange position he's found himself in
and that we as observers find ourselves
in because he was you know taking all
that money from adelon which is you know
Supreme sort of
maximal uh genocidal Zionism and they
wanted uh you know reportedly annexation
of the West bank so he was pretty
clearly a thw of the Israel Lobby and if
you read some of James bamford's work
and and some of the analysis of it it
seems that Israel may have been behind
the hack of Hillary's emails and and and
things at least they had Advanced
knowledge and almost no one has paid any
attention to that angle of the story but
that seems to be the one explanation
that would actually explain what
happened and why Trump would never get
to the bottom of it despite having the
power of the justice department and the
security agencies like why would he have
never been able to solve that mystery of
how these things got hacked but then if
you think well was it Israel and then
you're like oh well that would that
would actually explain it so you've got
that aspect too which is very strange um
and the fact that Trump when he takes
office he uh seems to scold Netanyahu
and he played that Jeffree Sachs clip of
Netanyahu being denounced very uh
seriously and and accurately by Jeff
Sachs um being as being essentially a
puppeteer of of of the US and bringing
it into these wars and so he seemed to
be realizing that the genocide in Gaza
was going to make be a bad look for him
as he takes office and so he wanted to
be The Peacemaker for a moment it looked
like and and compel or encourage Israel
to have a ceasefire although maybe their
own military situation made them want to
do that too it's hard to say uh but now
he's going back the opposite direction
and is you know is he just completely a
thall of the Israel Lobby is does he
possibly think that this is in the
National interest for the us to do this
or I mean what is it what's motivating
this decision by Trump which even as
much as all other presidents have had to
be uh you know Care at least careful if
not subservient to the Israel Lobby they
did not go this far so why is Trump
doing this how does this conform to any
conception of America
First wow yeah that's a good question
question and it's an important question
there are several theories uh today's
Washington Post for example said that
Jared Kushner is behind this I think
that's overestimating the uh the
intelligence and the capabilities of
Jared Kushner um perhaps this is from uh
Sheldon adon's uh Widow who gave Donald
Trump and the Trump campaign $150
million in addition to the $100 million
that adelon had given the Campa campaign
four years ago uh
so I don't know you I I believe that
deep
down uh Donald Trump is a is a Zionist
an Ardent Zionist his his daughter is an
orthodox Jew his son-in-law is an
orthodox Jew uh you remember he took
American uh Jews to
task uh for not supporting the
Republican party and saying that they
were traitors to Israel as if they were
Israeli citizens just bizarre statements
and I think that this combination of
extreme
Zionism and this notion that he's the
greatest dealmaker in the world has
deluded him into thinking that
everything he comes up with Visa the the
Middle East and the Middle East peace
process is a great idea it's this
Grand this grand plan for peace when
it's not and you know another thing I I
just returned from from Europe a couple
of days ago and I was reminded on this
trip that the United States is the only
Western Country that no longer supports
the two-state solution right and we
don't support the two-state solution
because the Israelis don't want us
to uh the two-state solution or frankly
in my own personal view a three-state
solution which would be Israel the West
Bank and
Gaza is the only way that there can ever
be peace uh in the region the isra Isis
have to allow the Palestinians
self-determination that's it you know
Martin Luther King said famously never
underestimate a man's desire to be free
and I can't think of anything that's
more appropriate than this example right
here Donald Trump though is is not the
guy to bring peace to the Middle East
the Abraham Accords Accords did not and
could not bring peace to the Middle East
When Donald Trump said in the 2016
election that he could solve the Middle
East problem in a day he meant by
screwing the Palestinians and that's
what the Abraham Accords were right you
encourage the Saudis to open diplomatic
relations you and uh you force force you
encourage the bahrainis the amadis the
tunisians the sudanes the Moroccans to
uh to establish diplomatic relations
with Israel and you just screw the
Palestinians and that's just not going
to work no matter how many times he
tries
it as brutal as they were with the Gaza
genocide under Biden they killed maybe
10% of the population yeah so I mean I
guess there may not be a lot of food
there now it's hard to say so they could
essentially have some A Renewed kind of
medieval Siege combined with aerial
Blitz cre that they like they have been
but what I
mean would would the world stand for
this I mean I I you have to wonder about
Europe if this could potentially
contribute to a break with the us
because NATO seems to
be uh dead at this point as a entity
that has any purpose or utility for its
members I mean is H how can this even I
I don't see how this can work in the
shorter or in the medium term even it's
if they're not going to they they can't
really relocate it doesn't seem that
they can relocate them to Jordan and
Egypt as they said or Indonesia and it
doesn't seem that they can just murder
them all time is time does not seem to
be on the Israelis and American side and
that seems to be in my opinion what was
the respon the reason for the response
in October 7 I to October 7 or maybe
even the reason why Israel facilitated
in some way the way that those attacks
unfolded I mean they the Hannibal
directive but also you know other steps
they took to sort of IGN or warnings for
the whole thing like they needed a they
wanted to do this I think because of
time they realized time is not on their
side because us unipolar moment is
fading and so I think that that you know
that seems to be logical and when you
look at what how brutal the uh zionists
are then you can't really put anything
past them anymore I mean they're they're
demonstrably guilty of genocide they
used to go you know the ADL and
everybody used to say oh that's a blood
liel that's a a blood liable how could
you but like they've killed so many more
children than anybody who accused them
of blood liable ever uh ACC or or
anybody who accused them of killing
children in the past would have accused
them of I mean no blood liel is as you
know deadly towards children as what
they've done in front of the whole world
so I feel like this this issue this
crumbling of American unipolarity you
know the the unipolar moment and the
imperative of a final solution for
Palestine this is coming together and
this is why we've seen what we've seen
since October 7 I agree and I I have two
thoughts on this I just returned from
Ireland and I think the Irish really
really get this this issue better than
than most other Western European
countries they have repeatedly condemned
Israeli actions in Gaza to the point
where um where the Israeli Ambassador
has been withdrawn from Dublin and the
Irish ambassador has been withdrawn from
Tel Aviv I think that's a good thing
because even in a small way it puts
pressure on the Israeli government and
it gives the rest of the Western
European countries a model with which to
address this problem number one number
two
uh I think that Donald Trump might be in
over his head at this early stage of
foreign policy think of it this way in
just the past what well he's been
president what two weeks now um he has
threatened to Annex Canada to which uh a
parliamentarian a Canadian
parliamentarian said go ahead and anex
us that's 60 electoral votes that that
are going to go blue and the Republicans
will never win another race ever again
so go ahead so number one they're
threatening he's threatening to anex
Canada number two he's threatening to
either Annex or somehow take over
Greenland as if we need green land where
we already have military bases and
number three Marco Rubio's first foreign
trip as secretary of state was to Panama
to threaten to take over the Panama
Canal now it's one thing to threaten
publicly oh we should take the canal we
we stole that Canal fair and square it's
another thing to go and to repeat that
privately now this may be a negotiating
tactic but that's not how the rest of
the world is seeing it they're seeing it
as a military threat
well if you're going to threaten Panama
and threaten Canada and threaten Denmark
which owns
Greenland then what makes you think
that's going to encourage those
countries or others close to them to
support your militarist position on Gaza
so I think that he's weakening himself
while at the same time believing that
his
bellicosity is encourag enaging other
countries to Rally to the American side
it's just not
happening no it's not and you know
there's a lot of debate about why the US
is so wedded to
Zionism and to my mind it is very
antithetical to the National interest
and so people that are saying that oh
the U that Israel is just doing the US
bidding they're the aircraft carryer in
the Middle East and they they say that
because people like Joe Biden have said
that in the past and even RFK Jr made
that argument at one point but I just
think about it as okay if you're job is
to Flack for Israel I mean are you going
to say that they're useless and that
they don't and that all we do is throw
money at them for no you know no real
benefit to us no you're not going to do
that you're going to come up with some
sort of rationale for why Israel is
somehow helpful so I don't know why
suddenly people on the left say like aha
look this is it it's they're helping us
like of course people that are flxs and
you know owned by the lobby are going to
say that Israel does good things for us
like for that it's in the National
interest but I mean what do you what
what I guess a lot of people's views
have hopefully evolved on this but why
do you think I and I don't think it's
either Israel controls the us or or the
US controls Israel but the US is an
oligarchy and Zionist oligarchs are very
invested in Zionism yeah in a in a way
that's even perhaps more intense than
like or the oil companies are interested
or oil oligarchs are necessarily focused
on just oil profits you know it's like a
it's a different project that they have
in mind and there's no counter to it of
people putting money into counter
Zionism institutions in the US so I mean
I guess where do you come down on the
reason for the US
disastrous uh you know alliance with
Zionism and Max greater Israel Zionism
correct me if I'm wrong Aaron because
you have a you have a clearer historical
uh understanding of this but it's it's
always been my understanding that this
this policy of of blind support for
Zionism and for Israeli Zionism in
particular began during the Nixon
Administration it was it was after
Nixon's election in 1968 after the 1967
war that Nixon decided that we would
support Israel without any question and
uh that's been the policy ever since if
you look back to statements made by for
example President Truman upon the
founding of the state of Israel um
through Eisenhower and Kennedy and
Johnson even there was more of a of a
fair balance uh between Israel and the
interests of the Palestinians that went
away with Nixon number one number
two I went to Israel for the very first
time in 2022 I went twice in
2022 and one of the things that struck
me was as you're as you're walking
through the old city of of Jerusalem the
Wald city um you know it's divided into
quarters there's the the Muslim quarter
the Jewish quarter the Christian quarter
and the Armenian quarter which didn't
make any sense to me but anyway that's
it so you walk through the Jewish
quarter and it is
absolutely spotless
the Muslim quarter is a [__] hole and I
think it's meant to be like that but one
of the things that was really
notable was when you enter the the
Jewish quarter and you get closer and
closer to the Western Wall um you start
seeing you start seeing signs where this
you know this magnificent Center is uh
brought to you by the adelen family and
This Magnificent museum is brought to
you by the Schwarz family and this one
is brought to you by so and so family so
there are millions and millions and
millions of dollars from American Jews
that went to renovate the Jewish
quarter um another thing that was
interesting to me was hand bills that
had been glued to the wall only in the
Jewish quarter and they said America we
are with you
what the heck is that supposed to mean
first of all I I don't want them to be
with us but what exactly was it supposed
to mean they're with us on what how
about you guys fight your own battles
and we'll fight our own battles thank
you very much but there's this
propaganda that is all over the place
that I think was probably meant to be
more subtle than it actually is and then
when you go into these outside the The
Old City you go into these
extremist Jewish nationalist
neighborhoods you see this kind of thing
everywhere banners with with you know uh
netanyahu's face and Trump's face or
with idar Ben gav's face and Trump's
face with uh an American hand shaking an
Israeli hand it it it's it's
overwhelming the level of propaganda
that you see uh all over the city of
Jerusalem it was really offputting to
me right yeah I've seen those too and
that you can find uh I've seen pictures
of American flags flying in Israel and
such it's weird yeah yeah it is and this
new aggressive posture I mean the the
the Israelis themselves there's a
Caitlyn Johnson column today where she
says a poll by the Jewish people policy
institut found that more than eight out
of 10 Jewish Israelis support the plan
proposed by Trump to ethnically cleanse
Gaza Strip sure and uh so free land free
land for more settlers right and if
you've seen um Abby Martins recorded
these interviews of people uh in
Jerusalem and the the median Israeli
seems to be essentially uh H have a you
know a lowercase in Nazi mentality I
mean I just I don't know the labens
round the master race like the unter
mention it's all there right in front of
us yeah ask any Israeli 2-year-old what
do you think should be done with the
Palestinians and they'll tell you we
should kill them all they'll tell you
right out straight out to your face we
should kill them all and that's the
average Israeli that's out there saying
that and you know what I think it's
because they've been emboldened by US
policy and I'm not just blaming Donald
Trump here the Democrats are just as
guilty yeah yeah and and uh this would
seem to be not acceptable for the I mean
it's the the for the Democrats to be
involved in this is weird because
they've they've embraced kind of woke
branding in a in a way that probably has
hurt them because they kind of have
overshot the the median of the American
public you know on some of these these
things uh but yet I mean the opposite of
of being woke or aware of Injustice in
the world and in any ex to any extent is
what genocide of small children and
seeing kids with their skulls exploded
again and again are snipers just sniping
kids on purpose which they've been doing
I
mean this this contradiction for the
Democrats do they have any wherewithal
at all or do they have I mean I've heard
them saying that like John fedman might
be the future of the party I mean I
think that they've lost their minds I
think that they don't understand how
much especially the younger generation
just sees them as accomplices to kind of
a a Nazi style evil I'll tell you I I
sent John fed's campaign $50 when he was
running for the Senate and I don't know
six months ago I I wrote The Campaign a
letter and I said I want my 50 bucks
back you Zionist liar phony um of course
I didn't get any response but God forbid
if John fedman were to be the future of
the democratic party um but let's talk
about that for a second because I think
that's a very important issue that you
raise here can you imagine being inside
the kamla Harris campaign and saying
well on the one hand there's a genocide
happening in Gaza but on the other hand
they are Jewish and we're supposed to be
pro-jewish and I proudly describe myself
as a Zionist despite the fact that
literally every single one of our
European allies thinks that this is a
mistake so I'm going to go with the
israelies on this one and then they
can't fathom how they lost Michigan and
Pennsylvania they can't fathom it
yesterday just yesterday Hakeem
Jeff and it shouldn't be lost on us that
the Man's first name is hakee which is a
Muslim name um Hakeem Jeff
reiterated the fact that he is a Zionist
and that the the Democratic caucus and
the House of Representatives supports
Israeli Zionism
why what has Zionism done for the
Democratic party other than to push it
off to the side and make it
irrelevant when when are the Democrats
or when is anybody else in this country
going to stand up for human rights and
stand against genocide have we learned
nothing from history apparently we we
haven't yeah I think it's in the
Democrats uh DNA unfortunately uh and it
goes back to the the teamsters The
Syndicate uh the corruption of the
democratic party they people don't
understand what was going on in the
postwar era and the pre-war years really
that led to labor being intertwined with
organized crime and organized crime with
in the personage of Myer lsky especially
yes being
intertwined with Zionism and uh and with
the you know the the the teamsters as a
big part of that as well the sort of
Teamster Lansky thing with Italian
selling drugs and then lansi uh
laundering laundering the money yeah
it's like we have a history we're more
of a mafia State I think the oligarchy
of the US is more of a mafia kind of a
thing than we want to admit and a lot of
the money from that era the drug money
and the money that came from the casinos
which were also fueled by drug La moneya
laundering this got gets put into other
legitimate
Enterprises uh including military
contracts like the tfx and General
Dynamics which was owned by Henry Crown
which was essentially Chicago outfit
which is Syndicate right I mean we are a
mobbed up country and Harry Truman gave
Lansky the the the presidential medal of
freedom in 1945 in a secret ceremony and
I just read that there was this Sheriff
there was a gangster named Paul Roland
Jones and I'm this is I'm reciting this
or recalling this from Peter Del Scott's
very dense but but amazing book deep
politics and the death of JFK there was
a a Shar
who was going to take a bribe from a
Syndicate guy in Dallas in 1946 right
before Ruby moves in uh and he was
saying that if he did this he told the
sheriff of Dallas that if he were to
take this bribe and allow The Syndicate
to set up in Dallas that he would have
Harry Truman write a an endorsement of
his
reelection so my God I mean this is how
uh so it's in the Democrats sort of DNA
and I think that's part of what was
happening with the k I if you want to
say that they had some selfish
motivations for going after the teamers
and such it was that they could clean
out that part of the democratic party if
they did that right and and change it
but they didn't they failed they failed
and they basically after they fail they
they they basically erased the teamsters
and uh Bobby Kennedy's Enemy Within
thesis about The Syndicate in the United
States and they just say oh it's this
Italian thing it's the mafia and forget
about all that so we we've never really
grappled with any of this like I I think
that we don't understand how corrupt at
a fundamental level American capitalism
is and the and once you take it Global
and you're pursuing Global
Imperium the the this oligarchy has more
money than any collection of people in
human history more wealth and power and
yet the the world has changed and I I
feel like they're dinosaurs so when Mar
Rubio is saying okay America may not be
a unipolar power anymore but we can we
can be a multi-power world of great
Powers multi-polar world of great Powers
but this is just more I think him saying
that we're going to be our this is this
is going to be our Mafia fom in the
Western Hemisphere I mean that's one way
to understand this which would then
explain Trump's statement about uh
having no desire to protect Taiwan you
know on the one hand I think it's great
that Trump at least claims that he want
doesn't want to be bogged down in Wars
around the country around the world
rather great totally agree I actually am
supportive of a multi-polar world I
think it's great um I think it uh I
think it gives us a better chance at at
a Global Peace than the United States
being this uh this
hedgemon but then at the same
time it also ought to lead to a desire
for good relations with China and Russia
and any other upand cominging uh world
power like like bricks for example
bricks as an organization and we're just
not seeing that it's one thing to say ah
screw the Taiwanese we don't really have
any national interests there we actually
don't have very many national interests
there it's really not our problem I
don't really care one way or the other
but then at the same time isn't it isn't
it
pro-american to want good relations with
China because our economies are so
closely
intertwined and good relations would
allow us to cut defense
spending why did the Chinese have bullet
trains and we don't why do the Chinese
have uh have construction programs all
around the world and we don't right it's
because we spend all of our money on
weapons and why aren't we trying to to
improve relations with Russia right now
I think we should be we should be laser
focused on improving relations with
Russia if we're serious about this
multi-polar world that should be leading
to
peace right and if Trump I mean even the
even his actions in the Middle East are
contradictory because he's announced
that he wants to pull out of Syria I
mean maybe is is he thinking that this
is going to be okay I mean my optimistic
perhaps delusionally optimistic but I
really only I'm not I don't really think
this is likely I'm just putting it out
there as a possibility but my hope is
that perhaps Trump is thinking that okay
we do need to retrench we do need to
basically have Monroe Doctrine as the
renewed basis of US foreign policy
because the the global Empire project
has failed but we have we or I
personally have these commitments to
Israel so we're going to give them a go
we're going to be as you know but I I I
hope we're going to be as aggressive as
we can and trying to like deal with this
because we need to do to do it now or
we're not going to be able to do it
because of where all the trends are
going so in some way he and people like
Rubio are responding to some Salient
facts about geopolitical reality and
that maybe this will fail and that he
will say well I I did my best we can't
go to war with Iran everyone tell the
the unanimous consensus is that it would
be a disaster uh and it would hasten the
end of us the of us Global dominance and
this would guarantee Israel's defeat I
mean the L because what they really need
to do which may result hopefully would
result in the end of a Zionist entity
over there would be What Jeffrey Sach
says which is to use the UN to just
create a Palestinian State and make it a
full member State on pr67 borders you
could do that and that wouldn't make
everything perfect right away but it
would allow them to have diplomatic
relations with other countries exactly
uh it would allow them to have trade
Gaza to have trade with the rest of uh
the world you know they wouldn't be have
this blockade and I think it could
potentially lead to a civil war in
Israel because of what you would have to
do with the settlers in the West Bank
like they would know that they were on
limited time and needed to have an Exit
Plan and then what would they do would
that lead to a civil war in Israel and
the end of you know Israel as a Zionist
ethnostate and maybe some Jewish people
who aren't psychotic and who can stomach
the thought of living with Palestinian
the Palestinians of pales
maybe they would stay and there could be
a you know a pluralistic society uh and
a one state or something like that but
you know is is Trump going is Trump
going to back Trump has these aspects of
his policy that seem to suggest that
suggest he is aware of the situation of
the US that that the unipolar moment is
fading maybe this is just Bluster to try
and and give Israel the best chance but
and the he will step away from the abyss
but do you think he will go to war with
with Iran and you know get involved more
deeply in Palestine Lebanon Yemen
potentially there's a resistance in Iraq
I mean what what do you think they will
do if it comes down to it if they face
resistance here how far will Trump go
for Israel this is the
question in the second half of this
episode John and I discussed Trump's
order to declassify JFK assassination do
ments as well as the continued relevance
of 9/11 in the context of the zionists
final solution for Palestine and the
western-backed alada Takeover of Syria
if you would like to hear the rest of
this episode please subscribe to the
American exception podcast on patreon
the URL is patreon.com American
exception either way please kindly like
this video And subscribe to this
American exception
Channel thanks to Dana chavaria for
producing this episode and thank you for
tuning in the US is a dying Empire run
by evil people this is why everything in
the US is so insane if we are objective
it's better that the US be a dying
Empire run by evil people than a
thriving Empire run by evil people at
least the former holds out the hope that
with the eventual death of the Empire
the evil people might not be the most
powerful actors in the world
alternatively in order to hold on to
their empire they could destroy the
human species with nuclear weapons or
biological warfare
it's too bad that there's no us left to
organize a US majority against an
oligarchic regime that does not serve
the interests of the majority a lot of
social cultural political manipulation
has been deployed to allow such a tiny
minority to rule over a nominal
democracy capitalism really is top- down
rule by an oligarchy of wealth the
condition of the West today settles the
argument the US hides most of its
Lawless despotism with state secret and
clandestine statecraft we can call this
a parap fascist system it is different
from Italian or Nazi style variants but
the function is the same absolutist
violence to protect the oligarchic
Imperial regime on the surface Maga
seems to Mark the emergence of a more
overt
fascism I someone who since 2009 has
intensely studied the Lawless us Empire
as such it bothers me to hear so-called
mainstream people freaking out about
Maga when so many unbelievably Sinister
things are done by the US Empire day in
day out decade after decade since World
War II ended I hope that we will see
Trump simply fail in each of the main
Arenas where he's trying to save the
dying Empire on behalf of its evil
owners Trump May admire Andrew Jackson
but the world does not approve of
Palestinian removal the US has no basis
to dictate any ter terms to Russia over
Ukraine a country that the US has
wrecked beyond measure a war with Russia
would be the end of the world the US
cannot attack Iran without the far most
likely outcome being a catastrophe for
the US and the world fighting a war with
China over Taiwan which the US and China
both agree as part of China would be a
disaster for the world Taiwan most of
all with Trump's rear guard actions
failing and the US increasingly exposed
around the world as the dying Empire run
by evil people that it is will the US
find it easier or more difficult to
dominate its nearest and dearest
historical victims the peoples of Latin
America and can the US oligarchy still
maintain control over us society when
the US economy has the Imperial rug
pulled out from underneath it will the
US oligarchs and the US public tolerate
the us being such a dysfunctional and
failing society when other parts of the
world are seeing societies improve often
dramatically in historic
terms they hope that perhaps AI can save
them that somehow it will be the Silver
Bullet to allow them to establish some
utopian system of cyber feudalism
utopian for them dystopian for the
99% the oligarchs of corporate wealth
will be the Cyber feudal Lords naturally
I think that they will fail the greed
and lawlessness of the US oligarchy
represents the worst of humanity they
literally Aspire or aspired at least
until recently to lawlessly rule the
whole world indefinitely in order to
acquire as much wealth and power as
possible these are the organizing
principles of the US Empire or the white
West whatever we want to call it the
egotism of the West is a cancer for
Humanity Emanuel Todd is correct and I
early earlier argued the same basic
thing in American exception Empire in
the Deep State the best hope for
International Peace and progress is the
end of us Imperial power in other words
if the US is ever to see peace and
Justice Prevail in any meaningful sense
the US Empire must first lose on the
devil's chessboard